以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
好的，所以这个大麻省理工学院我只是来自一个
okay so this big MIT I just came from a
教师很棒的教师安迪低
faculty terrific faculty member Andy low
在斯隆学校和我必须
in in the Sloan School and I have to
告诉你他告诉我们的是什么，然后我有
tell you what he told us and then I had
在他解释之前我不得不离开
I had to leave before he could explain
为什么这是真的，但这就像是一个
why it's true but this is like an
我不想要的惊人事实
amazing fact which I don't want to
忘了所以在这里你去这就是一切
forget so here you go this is everything
将在该板所以它是很
will be on that board so it's it's it's
关于我们或其他人的观察
an observation about us or other people
也许不是我们，但假设你有一个
maybe not us but so suppose you have a
有偏见的硬币也许你不是人
biased coin maybe you don't the people
玩这个游戏不知道，但它
playing this game don't know but it's
75％的人可能生产25％的头部
75% likely to produce heads 25% likely
产生尾巴然后玩家有
to produce tails and then the player has
猜到一个接一个的翻转
to guess for one flip after another
头或尾，如果你得到一美元
heads or tails and you get a dollar if
如果你是的话，你支付一美元是对的
you're right you pay a dollar if you're
错了，所以你只想得到尽可能多的
wrong so you just want to get as many
从这枚硬币中做出正确的选择
right choices as possible from this coin
继续翻转所以你应该怎么做
flip that continues so what should you
做得好，我想我希望我们会这样做
do well what I guess I hope we would do
我们不知道是什么
is we would not know what the
概率是如此我们猜测
probabilities were so we would guess
也许是第一次尾巴的头
maybe heads the first time tails the
第二次前往第三次
second time heads to the third time and
等等，但实际结果却是
so on but the actual result would be
大多是头
mostly heads
所以我们会在某些方面学到这一点
so we would learn at some point that
或许也许不会那么快我们
maybe maybe not quite as soon as that we
最终会知道我们应该这样做
would eventually learn that we should
继续猜测正确然后我们
keep guessing heads right and then we
那将是我们的最佳选择
would be that would be our optimal
战略猜测头所有的时间，但
strategy to guess heads all the time but
人们实际上做了什么，他们确实开始
what do people actually do they do start
像这样，然后他们
like this same way and then they're
开始学习头脑更多
beginning to learn that heads is more
很常见，也许他们的头脑比
common so maybe they do more heads than
尾巴，但有时尾巴是正确的
tails but sometimes tails is right and
然后过一小会儿，他们也许看到
then after a little while they maybe see
是的，或者他们很好
that it's yeah or they're just well
也许他们不算他们只是
maybe they're not counting they're just
像普通人一样经营
like operating like ordinary people
普通人实际上做了什么
and what do ordinary people actually do
从长远来看，你会说猜
in the long run you would say guess
每次都对，但他们没有
heads every time right but they don't in
从长远来看，人们也许是动物
the long run people and maybe animals
无论猜测是四分之三
and whatever guess heads three-quarters
的时间，并在尾部四分之一
of the time and tails one quarter at a
他们的时间并不令人难以置信
time isn't that unbelievable they're
四分之一的时间猜测尾巴
guessing tails a quarter of the time
当赔率永远不会改变的时候
when the odds are never changing anyway
这就是经济学家的观点
that's that's something that economists
和其他人必须解释和
and and other people have to explain and
如果我能再住一小时
if I had been able to stay another hour
我可以告诉你这个解释
I could tell you about the explanation
但无论如何，那就是我看到的
but anyway that's that's I I see I've
写在我没有的板上
written that on a board that I have no
埋葬的方式，所以它会在那里
way to bury so it's gonna be there and
它不是1806年的主题，而是
it's not the subject of 1806 five but
它有点令人惊奇，所以有
it's kind of amazing right so there's
良好的数学问题无处不没关系我可以
good math problems everywhere okay can I
只要离开你我所知道的和
just leave you with what I know and and
如果我了解更多，我会回到那里
if I learn more I'll come back to that
问题没关系
question okay
请注意这种方式
please turn attention this way right
Norm在规范上有点说几句
Norm's a little a few words on norms
就像那个应该是你的一句话
just like that should be a word in your
语言，所以你应该知道它是什么
language and so you should know what it
意思是你应该知道他们是少数
mean and you should know they're a few
重要的规范再一个规范是一个
of the important norms again a norm is a
测量矢量或大小的方法
way to measure the size of a vector or
矩阵的大小或a的大小
the size of a matrix or the size of a
张紧我们拥有的任何东西或功能
tensor whatever we have or a function
非常重要的是规范
very important the norm would be a
功能就像正弦X从零到PI
function like sine X from zero to PI
那个函数的大小是多少？
what would be the size of that function
好吧，如果它是两个正弦x的大小
well if it was two sine x the size would
两倍，所以规范应该
be twice as much so the norm should
反映，但昨天或
reflect that but so yesterday or
星期三我告诉你那里有P.
Wednesday I told you the so there P
等于1实际无穷大然后
equals to 1 actually infinity and then
我要用一个零的标准
I'm gonna put in the zero norm with a
问号，因为你会看到它
question mark because you'll see it's
它有问题，但让我公正
that it has a problem but let me just
从上次回忆起这些是P
recall from last time so these are the P
等于2是通常的平方和
equal to two is the usual sum of squares
平方根通常长度的向量P.
square root usual length of a vector P
这是一个非常重要的规范
equal one is this very important norm so
我们称之为l1规范，我们会看到
a we call that the l1 norm and we'll see
很多我真正提到过的
a lot of that that really I mentioned
它起着非常重要的作用
that it plays a very significant part
现在在压缩传感中它确实是一个
now in compress sensing it really was a
信号处理中的重磅炸弹
bombshell in signal processing to
发现和在其他领域
discover and in other fields to to
发现有些东西确实有效
discover that some things really work
在l1规范中做得最好
well work best in the l1 norm the
最大规范有自然的作用
maximum norm has a natural part to play
我们会看到它或它的矩阵模拟
and we'll see that or its matrix analog
所以我没有提到l0规范
so I didn't mention the l0 norm all this
LP业务因此LP规范
LP business so the LP norm
或者对于任何P，你是否获得了力量
or for any P is you take the piece power
在这里，P是2和
to the piece power up here P was 2 and
你拿这块根也好吧
your take the piece root so maybe I
应该把它写在P的那个上面
should write it to the one over P that's
然后那样
then that way
以片断力量和片断为基础我们
taking piece powers and piece roots we
得到两个V的标准有一个因素
do get the norm of two V has a factor
两个比较V的标准，所以P等于
two compared to the norm of V so P equal
到2你看到我们做对了
to 2 you see that we've got it right
那里的P等于你在这里看到的
there P equal one you see it here
因为它只是它的总和
because it's just just sum of the
绝对值人们无穷，如果我要是
absolute values people infinity if I if
我向上和向上移动P它会选择
I move P up and up and up it will pick
你知道，因为我增加P无论哪个
out you know as I increase P whichever
一个是最大的将要采取
one is biggest is going to just take
结束，这就是为什么你达到最大规范
over and that's why you get to max norm
现在，我正在使用零标准
now there's zero norm where I'm using
你会看到这个词不正确
that word like improperly as you'll see
因为如果是这样的话，那是什么呢？
because if so what is the 0 norm it's
所以它是非零的数量
the so so it's the number of non-zeros
它的非零组件就是它
of nonzero components its it it's the
你想知道有关的事
thing that you'd like to know about in
稀疏性的问题确实存在
question of sparsity does the is there
只有一个非零组件或那里11
just one nonzero component or there 11
你有什么样的可能吗？
are there 101 like what that you might
想要最小化，因为稀疏
want to minimize that because sparse
向量和稀疏矩阵很多
vectors and sparse matrices are much
你得到了很好的计算速度更快
faster to compute with you've got good
东西，但现在我声称这不是一个常态
stuff but now i claim that's not a norm
在0非零分量的数目
in the number of 0 nonzero components
因为什么是对如何做规范
because what's the norm of to how does
2V的标准与规范比较
the norm of 2v compare with the norm of
伏0规范这将是相同的到V
V the 0 norm it would be the same to V
具有相同数量的非零值
has the same number of non-zeros as
所以它违反了规范，所以我
so it violates the rule for a norm so I
想一想这些规范和所有的豌豆
think with these norms and all the peas
实际上是数学之间
in between so actually the the math
论文充满了让P介于1之间
papers are full of let P be between 1
和无限，因为那是
and infinity and because that's the
在那里，你做的范围内有一个适当的标准为
range where you do have a proper norm as
我们会看到，我认为好的事情
we will see I think the good thing to do
这些规范是有一个画面中
with these norms is to have a picture in
你的思想规范的几何是真实的
your mind the geometry of a norm is real
是好的所以我要建议的图片
is good so the picture I'm gonna suggest
是绘制所有的矢量让我们说在2d
is plot all the vectors let's say in 2d
所以二维空间或两个所以我
so two dimensional space or two so I
想要绘制他们所拥有的向量
want to plot then the vectors they have
V在这些不同的规范中等于1
V equal one in these different norms so
让我问你这是什么，这里是2d空间
let me ask you what so here's 2d space
r2现在我想绘制所有的
r2 and now I want to plot all the
具有普通l2的向量
vectors that have the ordinary l2
长度等于一个，这样又有什么
lengths equal one so what does that
图片看起来像我只是想一张照片
picture look like I just think a picture
真的是值得的东西它是一个圆
is really worth something it's a circle
谢谢它是一个圆圈，这是一个圆圈
thanks it's a circle it's a circle this
圆是这是当然的方程式
circle is that's the equation of course
v1平方加v2平方1以便我
v1 squared plus v2 squared 1 so that I
会称之为单位球
would call that the unit ball for the
现在规范或其他任何东西都可以
norm or whatever is is a circle okay now
现在这里更有趣了
now here comes more interesting what
关于在l1所以再次告诉我如何
about in the l1 so again tell me how to
绘制所有具有V1加V点
plot all the points that have V 1 plus V
2等于1什么是边界
2 equal 1 what what what's the boundary
现在看起来就像是让我们一样
gonna look like now it's gonna be let's
看清楚我可以把一定数量的
see well I can put in a certain number
那里有一个点和那个点
of points there one and there one and
那里是负一号那里
there at minus one and there
这个就是那个
this one there was that would be the
将反映向量10的向量
vector that would reflect the vector 1 0
这将反映向量0
and this would reflect the vector 0
减去1所以是OK所以这些都是像
minus 1 so yeah ok so those are like
四点易于绘图容易看到
four points easy to plot easy to see
l1规范，但是什么是完整的
that the l1 norm but what's the full
那是什么呢？剩下的边界是什么
what so what's the rest of the boundary
这是一颗钻石，它是钻石
here it's a diamond good it's a diamond
这是我们所拥有的线性设定为等于一起来
it's we have linear set equal to one up
这里是正象限
here in the positive quadrant
它只是V1加上V2等于1
it's just V 1 plus V 2 equal 1 in the
这个图是一条直线所以
graph of that is a straight line so all
这些家伙这是V的所有要点
these guys this is all the points with V
1加上V2等于1并且在这里和
1 plus V 2 equal 1 and over here and
在这里和这里所以单位球
over here and over here so the unit ball
在l1规范中是钻石，那是一个
in the l1 norm is a diamond and that's a
它反映在一个非常重要的图片
very important picture it reflects in a
简单的东西很简单
simple very simple way something
重要的是l1规范和
important about the l1 norm and the
因为它刚刚爆炸了他
reason it's just exploded him in
重要的是让我继续下去
importance let me continue though what
关于Max或V无穷大的最大范数
about the max norm the Max or V infinity
又是什么让我策划这些家伙
what so again let me plot these guys
这些家伙肯定会参与其中
these guys are certainly gonna be in it
他们再次归零
again they're zero
你知道加减我和加号
you know the plus or minus I and plus or
减去那些是好朋友的J是什么
minus J that are good friends what's the
边界的其余部分现在看起来像现在
rest of the boundary look like now now
这就是这意味着什么是最大的
this is this means max so what what are
你看到它的其余部分
the rest of the points you see it does
稍微想一想，然后你就明白了
take a little thought but then you get
它，你不要忘记它，所以
it and you don't for forget it ok so
什么是我正在寻找的东西
what's what's up I'm looking so suppose
最大值是V1
the maximum is V one
我想你要去II认为这是
I think you're gonna go I I think it's
看起来像那样的外出-一个
gonna look like that out - out - one
零和零到一，在这里
zero and up to zero one and up here the
矢量将是一个点
vector would be one one point for
所以最大的东西就是一个
something so the maximum would be one is
那真是太好了，不知怎的
that okay so so so somehow what really
看到你更改这个数字P你
sees as you change this number P you
从一个人或者daimond开始吧
start with people one or daimond and it
有点膨胀成为P的一个圆圈
kind of swells out to be a circle at P
等于2然后它保持
equal to 2 and then it kind of keeps
膨胀为P等于平方
swelling to be a square at P equal
无限，这是一个有趣的
infinity that's a that's a interesting
事情，是的，现在是什么问题
thing and yeah now what's the problem
0标准点在哪里
with the 0 norm where are the points
一个非零所以所以我正在密谋
with one non zero so so so I'm plotting
球在哪里在哪里
ball where are the where the where are
这个东西中的向量有一个
the vectors in this thing that have one
非零不是不为零非零使
non-zero not not zero nonzero so that
这不包括在内但我也是如此
that's not included and but I but so
我有什么
what do I have
我不允许向量三分之一
I'm not allowed the vector one-third
三分之二因为有两个非
two-thirds because that has two non
零，那么只有点数在哪里
zeros so where are the points with only
斧头上有一个非零的是啊
one nonzero yeah on the axes yeah that
告诉你，他可以在那里
does tell you so he can be there and
有没有好男人，当然这样的
there okay without guy and of course so
只是一直走出去，完全是这样
is just keep going out so it totally
违反你所知道的也许是重点
violates the you know so maybe the point
我应该对这些数字做些什么
that I should make about these figures
所以就像我去的时候发生的那样
so so like what's happening when I go
降到零我真的很满意
down to zero I'm served it really that
手指应该是在另一端向右
finger should be on the other end right
哦，不要拍这个家伙在中间
oh no shoot this guy's in the middle
这是一个画得很厉害的手指l2是善良的
this is a badly drawn finger l2 is kind
一个中心人l1是一端el
of a center guy l1 is the at one end el
在另一端和这一个的无限性
infinities at the other end and this one
已离开，左边那里
has gone off and the left there the the
钻石有没有发生在这里的事情
diamond has yeah what's happened here as
一个人走向零没有
that one goes down towards zero none of
这些都会好起来的这些这些这些
these will be okay these these these
球将或这些集将失去
balls will or these sets will lose
重量是啊所以他们总是会有这些
weight yeah so they'll always have these
指出，但他们会像这样
points in but they'll be like this and
然后像这样，然后终于在
then like this and then finally in the
在不可接受的限度但没有
in the unacceptable limit but none of
这些，这是没有任何好处的用户可以在本
those this was not any good either this
这是P等于一半让我们说排序
this was for P equal half let's say sort
呃那是P等于发生的那个
of uh that's a P equal to happen that's
不是一个好的规范是的所以也许是事情
not a good norm yeah so maybe the thing
你有这个圈子的属性
you so there's a property of the circle
钻石和广场是一个
the diamond and the square which is a
那些那些很好的数学属性
nice math property of those of those
三套，不属于此
three sets and is not possessed by this
因为这件事减肥我输了
as this thing loses weight I lose the
财产当然那是
property and then of course that's
完全迷失在那里你知道吗？
totally lost over there do you know what
那个属性将是它的本质
that property would be what what it's
为你凹凹凸我会
for you concave convex convex I would
说凸是真正的规范有凸
say convex this is true norm has convex
单球也许可能是我正在拿球
uni-ball maybe maybe for ball I'm taking
所有这些是啊所以我允许
all of these yeah so I'm allowing the
这些形状的内部所以这不是一个
insides of these shapes so this is not a
凸集，设置我不应该
convex set that set which I shouldn't
所以不是不凸会是这样一个与
so not not convex would be this one with
哦，这反映了事实哦
and that reflects the fact that the oh
规范的规则被打破了
the rules for a norm are broken the
三角不等式可能已被打破
triangle inequality is probably broken
那是的，我觉得有点像
and that yep I think that's sort of like
值得记住，然后再一个规范
worth remembering and then one more norm
这是很自然的思考
that's natural to think about is so s as
在广场问题中总是如此
in the Piazza question s does always
代表1806年的对称矩阵
represent a symmetric matrix in 1806
五，现在我要问我的规范是什么
five and now I'm gonna ask my norm is
将要这样我会称之为s
going to be so I'm gonna call it the s
规范，所以评估实际上它是一个
norm so asses up actually it's a
正定对称矩阵F是
positive definite symmetric matrix F is
一个正定的对称矩阵和
a positive definite symmetric matrix and
我该怎么办
what do I do
我会带V转置AVsV对不起好吧
I'll take V transpose AV s V sorry okay
我们的能量是什么呢？
what's our word for that the energy
这是在矢量V的能量和
that's the energy in the vector V and
我会采取平方根，以便我这样做
I'll take the square root so that I so
如果我，我现在有两个长度
that I now have the lengths of two if I
从V2到V的双V然后我得到2
double V from V 2 to V then I get a 2
这里和2在这里，当我拿这个
here and a 2 here and when I take this
平方根我得到一个整体两个和
square root I get a overall two and
这就是我想要的我想要的规范
that's what I want I want the norm to
与两个或三个线性增长或
grow linearly with the two or three or
无论我乘以什么，但是什么是
whatever I multiply by but what is the
这个东西的形状，什么是
shape of this thing so what is the
我会得到什么样的形状
what is the shape I'm gonna get a
像那样的形状是什么形状
picture like that so what is the shape
V转置的V等于或小于1
of V transpose s V equal one less or
如果s是正对称的，则等于1
equal one if s is a positive symmetric
正面的信件告诉我们，我声称
positive letters tell us I'm claiming
我们什么时候得到一堆规范
that we get a bunch of norms when do we
得到l2规范什么矩阵s会
get the l2 norm what what matrix s would
这给了我们l2标准的身份
this give us the l2 norm the identity
当然现在发生了什么事情发生，如果
certainly now what's going to happen if
我使用了一些不同的矩阵
I use some different matrix s this
圆圈会改变我的形状
circle is going to change shape I'm
会有不同的规范取决于
gonna have a different norm depending on
S和一个典型的情况下，将作为s等于
s and a typical case would be s equal to
3这是一个正定的对称
3 that's a positive definite symmetric
矩阵，和本，现在我会
matrix and this this now I would be
绘制2V1平方加上的图形
drawing the graph of 2 V 1 squared plus
3V2平方即能量
3 V 2 squared that would be the energy
对等，我只想要你
right equal one and I just want you to
告诉我这是什么形状，这是一个
tell me what shape that is so that's a
你可以检查的完美的规范
perfectly good norm that you could check
他们所有的财产都出来了
all its properties they all come out
很容易，但我得到一个新的图片新
easily but I get a new picture a new
你可以调整的规范
norm that's kind of adjustable you could
说它是加权范数权重的意思
say it's a weighted norm weights mean
你选择了一些
that you kind of have picked some
数字有点适合
numbers sort of appropriate to the
特别好的问题就是假设那些
particular problem well suppose those
数字是2和3是什么形状
numbers are 2 and 3 what shape is the
单位球在这个标准中它是椭圆形的
unit ball in this s norm it's in ellipse
对，它是一个椭圆，我猜它
right it's an ellipse and I guess it
实际上将是更大的数字3
will actually be so the larger number 3
好吧意味着你不能走得那么远
well will mean you can't go as far as
一个较小的数字-我认为它会
a smaller number - I think it would
可能是像这样的椭圆
probably be an ellipse like this and the
椭圆的轴长度
axes axis lengths of the ellipse would
可能与它有关-
probably have something to do with it -
在三个没关系，所以这就是现在你
in the three okay so that's just now you
真的知道所有的矢量规范
know really all the vector norms that
有点自然而然地使用这些
are sort of natural to use these come up
以自然的方式，他们就像我们说的一样
in a natural way they're all as we said
身份矩阵让我们回归
the identity matrix brings us back to
这两种规范都是如此
the two norm so these are all sort of
两种规范的变化
variations on the two norm
这些是P的变化，从1开始
these are variations as P runs from 1 up
2到无穷大，不允许
to 2 onto infinity and is not allowed to
低于1，那是规范然后
go below 1 okay that's norms and then
也许你实际上可以从这个看
maybe you can actually see from this
图片在这里，我们有点喜欢
picture here's our like somewhat hokey
为什么它是该规范的想法
idea of why it is that this norm
最小化那里或最小化
minimizing the so minimizing there or in
这个规范所以我在这里的意思是什么
this norm so what do I mean by that here
将是一个典型的问题最小化
would be a typical problem minimize
受到斧头等于B的l1哦对不起
subject to ax equal B the l1 oh sorry
我正在使用X现在是l1的一个标准
I'm using X now yeah one norm of the l1
X的规范，这将是一个重要的
norm of X so that would be an important
问题实际上它有一个名字的人
problem actually it has a name people
花了很多时间思考一个
have spent a lot of time thinking of a
快速解决它的方式几乎就像
fast way to solve it it's almost like
最小二乘法什么会什么会令
least squares what would what would make
它更像是这些正方形
it more like these squares would be
改变两个耶耶我能不能
change that to two yeah yeah can I just
有点像草图而不是一个大的
sort of like sketch without making a big
这里论证L之间的区别
argument here the difference between L
等于1或
equal 1 or
到这里，是的，我只是画一个
to here yeah just I'll just draw a
图片现在擦除这个椭圆但你
picture now erase this ellipse but you
不会忘记好的，所以这是我们的
won't forget okay so this this is our
问题l与l1它有一个着名的名字
problem l with l1 it has a famous name
基础追求
basis pursuit
在工作的人都很有名
well famous to people who work in
对于l2的优化它具有重要意义
optimization for l2 it has an important
好吧，它有点像这些
name well it's sort of like these
方块岭回归各种各样的
squares Ridge regression all sorts of
这就像一个漂亮的模特
the this is like a beautiful model
所有解决方案中的问题
problem among all solutions to ax
假设这只是一个等式
suppose this is just one equation like
c1x1加c2x2等于右侧
c1 x1 plus c2 x2 equals some right side
B所以X的约束表明了这一点
B so the X's the constraint says that
向量X必须是在一条线上
the vectors X have to be on a line
假设这是一个图表
there's suppose that's a graph of that
所有这些X中的哪一行
line so as among all these X's which one
是的我从来没有意识到我是什么
yeah I never realizing what is what I'm
要说是聪明的我的意思是好的
gonna say is gonna be smart okay I mean
没有它会是不错的不会是
not it's gonna be nice not gonna be
难
difficult
让我们做，我们知道最好的L2这样一个
let's do the one we know best l2 so
这是一条线让我放过的图片
here's a picture of the line let me let
我让它更倾斜一点
me make it a little more tilted so so
你是的是的，是的，就像二三
you yeah yeah yeah like like two three
好吧，这是XY平面，这里是X.
okay where this is the XY plane here's X
1这里有X2这对是
1 there's X 2 here are the pair of the
满足我的条件的点
points that satisfy my condition which
一个最小化该线上的哪个点
one minimizes which point on that line
最小化具有最小的l2范数
minimizes has the smallest l2 norm which
线上的点具有最小的l2
point on the line has the smallest l2
规范是的，你正在画右边
norm yeah you're drawing the right
用你的双手数字最小的l2
figure with your hands the smallest l2
要记住的规范L是多远的
norm L to remember is just how far out
你走
you go
就是这样
it's it's
在这里循环所以无所谓
circular here so it doesn't matter what
方向他们都给予同样的l
direction they all giving the same l
2-norm它只是我们有多远
2-norm it's just how far so we're
找对的最近点
looking for the closest point on the
因为我们不想去任何一条线
line because we don't want to go any
我们想要进入最小距离
further we want to go a minimum distance
有两个现在那么如果是这样哪来的点
with two now so if so where's the point
至少距离是啊它只是显示
at minimum distance yeah it's just show
我再一次用手或者再次
me again once more with hands or
无论我不想要什么
whatever it'll be that I didn't want
那里有45度角，我要擦掉
45-degree angles there I'm gonna erase
再次，真正这个时候我会
it again and really this time I'm gonna
获得不是45的角度
get angles that are not 45 all right
辉煌得到它，这是我的路线
brilliant got it okay that's my line
好的，最近的点是什么
okay and what's the nearest point in the
l2规范
l2 norm
这里是在L2赢家权
here's the winner in l2 right the
最近点每个人都看到了
nearest point everybody sees that
这就是你所知道的
picture so that's the that's you know
这是一个基本的图片为
that's a basic picture for for
用约束最小化某事
minimizing something with a constraint
这是根本问题
which is the fundamental problem of
神经网络的优化
optimization of neural nets of
我生活中的一切都很好
everything really of life well I'm
哲学这样好吗这是一个的，但
philosophical so okay that's that's but
当然，这总是意味着问题
of course it always mean the question
永远是，也许这在生活中是真实的
always is and maybe it's true in life to
你使用哪种规范好吧现在算了
which norm are you using okay now count
并与自己展示那是
and show with yourself that was the
最小的l2是最短的
minimum in l2 that's the shortest
距离意味着我们的距离
distance where a distance means what we
通常认为它是有意义但现在
usually think of it as meaning but now
让我们来看看指出的l1规范
let's go for the l1 norm which point on
这条线现在具有最小的l1范数
the line has the smallest l1 norm so now
如果是的话，我打算加两个
I'm going to add the two so if this is
有些人认为这是零点
some point a this is some point a zero
这是零点B的权利
and this is some point zero B right
那里
there
所以这两点显然是
so those two points are obviously
重要而且我们可以想到这一点
important and that point we could figure
出的公式
out the formula for
因为我们知道这是什么
because it's we we know what the
几何，但我只是把这两个
geometry is but I've just put those two
如此点我得到零B是的
points in so did I get a zero B yeah
这是一个零井，所以让我问一下
that's a zero well so let me just ask
你那个问题
you that question
那条线上的哪一点最小
what point on that line has the smallest
l1范数具有最小的l1范数
l1 norm which has the smallest l1 norm
有人说它只是说了一点
somebody said it just say it a little
大声，这样你就错了
louder so that you're wrong
磁带永远零B这一点是
tape forever zero B this point that's
获胜者，冠军
the winner
这是l1冠军，这就是
this is the l1 winner and this was the
l2获胜者并注意我说的话
l2 the winner and notice what I said
早些时候，我没有看到它的到来
earlier and I didn't see it coming but
现在我意识到这是一个手指放入
now I realize this is a finger to put in
获胜者最多的笔记
the notes the winner has the most zeroes
它是稀疏的向量，它有一个零
it's the sparse vector it's got a zero
它没有两个组件
well out of two components it didn't
有很大的自由，但它有零
have much freedom but it has a zero
零件
component
它坐落在上上它的轴
it sits on the on the on the axes it's
轴上的东西有
the things on the axes that have the
最小数量的组件，所以是的
smallest number of components so so yes
所以这是l2中的图片
so this is the picture in l2 in in two
抱歉，在二维图像，使
sorry the picture in two dimensions so
我在2d，你可以看到
I'm in 2d and you can see that the
获胜者是零组件是啊是啊
winner is has a zero component yeah yeah
并且这是一个延伸到的事实
and and that's a fact that extends into
更高的尺寸，这使得
higher dimensions too and that makes the
l1规范特别，因为我说是的
l1 norm special as I've said yeah is
还有更多关于这个例子的说法
there more to say about that example
这是一个简单的第二个问题
that's for a simple 2d question that
真的说明了l1
really makes the point that the l1
胜利者在那里它不是你
winner is there it's not further you
不要再上去行权
don't go further up the line right
因为因为那么你，那么你
because because then you're then you
甚至在各方面都很糟糕
have even that's bad in all ways when
你进一步上升，你正在添加
you go up further you're you're adding
有些非零
some nonzero
第一个组件，你正在增加
first component and you're increasing
非零超过第二个组成部分
the non zero over second component so
你的想法不错
your that's a bad idea
这是一个坏主意，这是这个
that's a bad idea this is this is the
赢家，在某种程度上是这里的图片
winner and in a way here's the picture
是的哦是的我应该准备这些
yeah oh yeah I should prepare these
讲座，但这一个都出来了
lectures but this one's coming out all
无论如何，所以这样的图片
right anyway so this so the picture
那里有最近的球
there is the nearest ball it's at that
点，你能看到什么呢？
point and what is it can you see that so
该星是外循环，这是
that star is outside the circle this is
l1冠军，所以这是最近的
the l1 winner so and that's the nearest
那就是那个爆发了
that's the that's is the blow-up of the
l1规范直到达到这一点为止
l1 norm until it hits that's the point
在l1规范命中你看到它只是
where the l1 norm hit do you see it just
给它一点想到的是
give it a little thought that that
另一种几何方式来看
another another geometric way to see the
你开始回答这个问题
answer to this problem is you started
原点然后你炸毁了一个规范，直到
the origin then you blow up a norm until
你得到一点就行了
you get a point on the line that
满足你的约束，因为
satisfies your constraint and because
当它击中时，你正在炸毁一个常态
you were blowing up a norm when it hits
首先，这是最小的爆炸
first that's the smallest blow-up
可能
possible
这是这家伙的那个薄荷
that's the mint that's the guy that
最小化你只是考虑一下
minimizes ya just think about that
图片，我会画得更好
picture and I'll draw it better
某处-那是矢量规范和
somewhere - well that's vector norms and
然后我介绍了一些矩阵规范和
then I introduced some matrix norms and
我只想说那些话
let me just say a word about those
关于矩阵规范的好话，所以
okay word about matrix norm so so the
矩阵规范是如此如此现在我有一个
matrix norms were the so so now I have a
矩阵a和我想定义那些相同的
matrix a and I want to define those same
对于矩阵而言这又是三个规范
three norms again for a matrix and this
是两个常态，两个标准是什么
was two norm and what was the two norm
一个矩阵很好，它是西格玛一个转身
of a matrix well it was Sigma one turned
是这样的，没有定义它
out to be so what that doesn't define it
或者它可以找到它只是说好吧
or it could to find it just say okay the
最大的奇异值是两个常态
largest singular value is the two norm
矩阵，但实际上它来自
of the matrix but actually it comes from
在某个地方所以我想谈谈这个
somewhere so I want to speak about this
首先是墓葬规范，所以它就是这样
one first the tomb norm so so so it's
矩阵的两个范数和一种方法
the two norm of a matrix and one way to
看矩阵的两个范数就是
see the two norm of a matrix is to
连接到我的2个矢量范数
connected to the 2 norm of vectors I'd
喜欢连接矩阵的两个范数
like to connect the two norm of matrices
向量的两个范数以及如何应用
to the two norm of vectors and how shall
我这样做，我想我会去看看
I do that I think I'm going to look at
AX的2范数超过X的两个范数
the 2 norm of AX over the two norm of X
所以对我来说这个比例是
so in a way to me that that ratio is
比如爆炸因子，如果a是7次
like the blow up factor if a was 7 times
如果一个人的身份是一个简单的案例
the identity to take an easy case if a
是7倍的身份会是什么那
is 7 times the identity what would that
比如是7如果是a如果a是7我这个
ratio be yeah 7 if a is if a is 7 I this
这将是7X，这将是X和
this will be 7 X and this will be X and
规范因素7出来了
norms the factor 7 comes out so that
比率将是7好
ratio will be 7 okay
对我而言，规范就是这样的
for me the norm is take that's the
爆炸因素，所以这里是我的
blow-up factor when so here here's my
这是我现在的矩阵规范的想法
here's the idea of a matrix norm now I'm
从矢量做矩阵矩阵范数
doing matrix matrix norm from vector
规范和答案将是最大的
norm and the answer will be maximum the
这个比率的最大值我称之为比率
maximum of this ratio I call that ratio
爆炸矢量只是一个
of the blow up vector that's just a
化妆品名称是所有X的最大值
made-up name the maximum over all X's
所有我想看看哪个矢量得到
all the I look to see which vector gets
炸得最多，这是常态
blown up the most and that is the norm
矩阵
of the matrix
我知道我已经接受了规范
I know I've I've settled on norms of
这是在楼上完成的
vectors that's that's done upstairs
现在我正在寻找规范
there now I'm looking at norms of
矩阵，这是获得一个的方法
matrices and this is one way to get a
矩阵的良好规范来了
good norm of a matrix that kind of comes
从这两个规范，所以会有
from the two norm so there would be
来自的矩阵的其他规范
other norms for matrices coming from
其他矢量规范和我们没有的规范
other vector norms and those we haven't
看到但这两个规范是非常的
seen but the two norm is this is a very
重要的是什么是最大的
important one so what is the maximum
矩阵的这个比率的值
value of this of that ratio for a matrix
声称它是Sigma1是什么的
a the claim is that it's Sigma 1 what a
那里的大平等现在可以看出原因
big equality there now can we see why is
为什么Sigma1能够解决这个问题
why is Sigma 1 the answer to this
问题我可以看到一对夫妇的方式来
problem I can see a couple of ways to
考虑一下，但那是非常的
think about that but that's a very
事实上这是一个重要的事实
important fact in fact this is a way to
发现西格玛1没有全部
discover what Sigma 1 is without all the
其他西格玛如果我寻找X那个
other Sigma's if I look for the X that
有最大的爆炸因素和
has the biggest blow-up factor and by
会是其中X的方式，其中X会
the way which X will it be which X will
在这里赢得最大的竞争，并成为
win the max competition here and be
Sigma的时间是1倍
Sigma 1 times as long
Raja的比例为Sigma1
Raja's as the the ratio will be Sigma 1
什么是西格玛1这是什么东西
that'll be Sigma 1 when is this thing
西格玛1倍大，对于其
Sigma 1 times as large as that for which
如果X是一个特征向量，则X为零
X naught for an eigenvector if X was an
特征向量是什么比例
eigenvector what would that ratio be
lambda但是如果a不是对称的
lambda but if a is not a symmetric
矩阵
matrix
也许特征向量不会告诉你
maybe the eigenvectors don't tell you
服务员准确的方式去做什么
the the waiter the exact way to go what
那么你现在猜的是什么向量视图
so what vector view would you now guess
它不是一个特征向量，它是一个单数
it's not an eigenvector it is a singular
矢量和哪些奇异向量
vector and which singular vectors are
可能会是你v1
probably going to be you v1
是啊V一个有意义的赢家所以
yeah V one makes sense winner so the
本次比赛的获胜者是X等于V.
winner of this competition is X equal V
1第一个右边的单数
1 the first the first right singular
矢量，我们最好能够检查
vector and we better be able to check
这又是一个最大化问题
that so again this maximization problem
答案告诉你的是
the answer tells you is in terms of the
奇异向量，这是一种寻找方式
singular vectors so that's a way to find
这第一个奇异向量没有
this first singular vector without
找到他们所有，让我们只是插入
finding them all and let's just plug in
他们向量的第一件事就是看
the first thing of their vector and see
这个比例是看到它看到的
that the ratio is see what it see that
这个比例是西格玛1所以现在让我插上
the ratio is Sigma 1 so now let me plug
它所以我有什么我想要一个V1
it in so so what do I have I want a V 1
超过V1的长度好吧，我希望
over length of V 1 okay and I'm hoping
得到答案的是什么回合
to get that answer well what's the bout
这里的分母是V的长度
of the denominator here the length of V
1是什么没什么大不了的还有那一个
1 is what no big deal there that's one
什么是顶部的长度
what what's the length of the of the top
一个如此
one so so
是V1那么什么是V1，如果v1是
is a v1 now what is a v1 if v1 is the
第一个奇异的第一个右奇异
first singular first right singular
向量然后v1是Sigma的1倍u1
vector then a v1 is Sigma 1 times u1
记住奇异的矢量交易了
remember the singular vector deals were
AV等于SigmauAVk等于sigmakUK
AV equals Sigma u AV k equals sigma k UK
记住，所以他们不是
remember that so they're not
特征向量是它们的奇异向量
eigenvectors their singular vectors so
这就是v1的长度
that's that is a v1 is the length of
西格玛1U1和它是由1和分
sigma 1 u 1 and it's divided by 1 and of
当然你也是一个单位向量，所以我
course u 1 is also a unit vector so I
只是得到信号好，这是另一个
just get signal okay so that's another
这样说，你可以找到西格玛1
way to say that you can find Sigma 1 by
解决这个最大的问题，你得到
solving this maximum problem and you get
西格玛1确定，我可以得到其他
that Sigma 1 ok and I could get other
规范矩阵规范通过最大化
norms matrix norms by by maximizing that
在那个向量范数I中炸毁因子
blow up factor in that vector norm I
现在不会这样做只是为了保持控制
won't do that now just to keep control
什么，我们现在得到了什么什么的
of what we've got now what were the what
是下一个进入的矩阵规范
was the next matrix norm that came in
最后的时间非常非常重要的一个
last time very very important one for
以某种方式深度学习和神经网络
deep learning and neural nets somehow
它比这家伙更简单一点，
it's a little simpler than this guy and
什么是矩阵规范
what's the what was that matrix norm
什么字母的名字在这里
what letter whose name goes here
Frobenius所以Frobenius和F的首都F
Frobenius so capital F for Frobenius and
这一点，那是什么那是
that and what was that that was the
平方根的总和
square root of the sum of the all the
加起来为所有人添加所有的IJ方块
add up add all the a IJ squares for all
在矩阵上然后取一个正方形
over the matrix and then takes a square
根，然后有人问了一个好
root and then somebody asked a good
周三课后问题是什么
question after class on Wednesday what
这与Sigma的关系有关
has that got to do with the Sigma's
因为我失望的是这些
because I my disappoint was that these
宿舍是随身携带的人
dorms are the guys that go with the
Sigma的做法很好
Sigma's that does that have nice
西格玛的公式就在这里
formulas for the Sigma's and here it is
它是总和的平方根
it's the square root of the sum of the
所有信号的正方形是对不起让
squares of all the signals yes sorry let
我再写Frobenius但是这个
me write Frobenius again but this
用F表示现在很漂亮
notation with an F is now pretty
标准，我们应该能够看到
standard and we should be able to see
为什么这个数字与那个数字相同
why that number is the same as that
号码是的，我可以给你一个
number yeah I could I could give you a
理由还是我不能把它放在上面
reason or I couldn't put it on the
问题集是啊我认为它更好
problem set yeah I think it better on
问题集首先是因为
the problem set because first of all
我脱身马上和
I'll get off the hook right away and
其次是中间的这种联系
secondly this connection between in
ProbieNia所以它就像一个美丽的事实
Probie Nia so it's like a beautiful fact
关于Frobenius规范，你加起来所有
about Frobenius norm that you add up all
SigmaSquared是他们的M倍
the Sigma Squared's as M times n of them
因为它是一个全部填充的矩阵或你
because it's a all filled matrix or you
加起来以另一种方式说它是我们
add up so another way to say it is we
还没写下今天的SVD
haven't written down the SVD today's a
谁你的西格玛V转置和重点
whoyou Sigma V transpose and the point
实际上就是弗罗贝尼乌斯的规范
is that for the Frobenius norm actually
对于所有这些规范，我可以改变你
for all these norms I can change you it
不改变常态，所以我可以做
doesn't change the norm so I can make
你们认同它就是我们所知道的
you the identity it's you as we all know
是一个正交矩阵，我是什么
is an orthogonal matrix and what I'm
说是正交矩阵，你没有
saying is orthogonal matrix you doesn't
改变任何这些特定的规范
change any of these particular norms so
假设这里的身份相同
suppose it was the identity same here
这可能是没有的身份
that could be the identity without
改变规范，所以我们到了
changing the norm so we're down to the
什么是弗罗贝尼乌斯的规范
norm of the the Frobenius so what's the
弗罗贝尼乌斯规范
Frobenius norm
那个家伙是什么ProbieGnaeus
of that guy what's the Probie Gnaeus
那个对角矩阵的范数很好
norm of that diagonal matrix well you're
应该把所有的正方形加起来
supposed to add up the squares of all
矩阵中的数字和做什么
the numbers in the matrix and what do
你让你做对了所以这就是原因
you get you get that right so that's why
这与此相同，因为
this is the same as this because the
正交人在那里正交
orthogonal guy there on the orthogonal
那个家伙在常态上没有任何区别
guy there make no difference in the norm
但这需要检查是的，但是
but that takes checking right yeah but
这是另一种了解原因的方法
that's another way to see why the
证明规范给出了这个然后
provenience norm gives this and then
最后这是核规范和
finally this was the nuclear norm and
实际上就在我的午餐前
actually just before the my lunch
讲授的大概的主题
lecture on the subject of probably about
午餐讲座是一个学习早晨
a learning morning the lunch lecture was
关于这种人类行为的疯狂方式
about this crazy way that humans behave
实际上不是我们，而是其他人
not us but other humans other actually
好吧，从磁带中拿出来好吧
well take that out of the tape yeah okay
无论如何那是那次讲座
anyway that was that lecture well before
这是一个小时的讲座加
that was a lecture for an hour plus
关于深刻学习的人
about deep learning by somebody who
真的真的已经开始明白了
really really has begun to understand
里面有什么东西发生了这是如何
what is happening inside how does that
梯度下降优化算法
gradient descent optimization algorithm
挑出什么什么它挑出来作为
pick out what what does it pick out as
随着作为东西它学习它的
that as as the thing it learns it's
会是你知道我们的目标
gonna be the you know our goal in in
这个课程我们还没有，但他的
this course we're not there yet but his
猜想是的，所以它是一个
conjecture is that that yeah so it's a
猜想他没有我们的证据
conjecture he doesn't have our proof
他有一些很好的案例证明
he's got proofs of some nice cases where
事情通勤，但他没有得到
things commute but he hasn't got the
整件事，但它非常棒
whole thing yet but it's pretty terrific
工作所以这是cerebro教授
work so this this was professor cerebro
在芝加哥所以他刚宣布了他的
in Chicago so he just announced his
猜想和他猜想的是
conjecture and his conjecture is that in
一个模型案例深入学习
a model case the deep learning that
我们将通过渐变来学习
we'll learn about with a gradient
我们将学会找到的血统
descent that we'll learn about to find
最重要的是重点
the best weights that the point is that
他们你知道典型的深度学习
they're you know typical deep learning
问题这几天有更多的
problem these days there are many more
方式比样本等都有很多
ways than samples and so there are a lot
可能的最小值
of possible minima
许多不同的重量给出相同的
many different weights give the same
最小的损失，因为有这么多
minimum loss because there are so many
权衡它的问题也是如此
weights it's the problem is like too
许多变量，但事实证明是一个
many variables but it turns out to be a
非常非常好的事情那部分
very very good thing that's part of the
成功，他认为，在一个
success and the he believes that in a
通过优化的模型情况
model situation that the optimization by
梯度下降挑出权重
gradient descent picks out the weights
这样可以最大限度地减少核规范
that minimize the nuclear norm so this
将是很多权重的标准
would be a norm of a lot of weights and
他认为这就是系统的用武之地
he thinks that's where the system goes
会看到这个出现了
will see this this was comes up in
我上次提到的压缩传感
compressed sensing as I mentioned last
这个时间，但现在我必须记住
time so this but now I have to remember
什么是定义做得好
what was what was the definition well do
你还记得核规范是什么
you remember what the nuclear norm was
这也是他经常使用的他用过的
it's also his he often used he used a
我会把小明星而不是结束
little star instead of an end I'll put
在其他人称之为的笔记中
that in the notes other people call it
跟踪规范，但我想这个
the trace norm that's but I think this
最后一种给它起一个名字符号
end kind of gives it a name notation you
还记得让我们叫它
can remember so let's call it the
核规范你还记得那是什么
nuclear norm do you remember what that
一个是
one was
是的，有人正在唱歌
it was yes somebody's singing it right
添加Sigma的耶只是总和
add the Sigma's yeah just the sum of the
像你这样的信号知道一个规范是的
signals like you know one norm yeah this
是一种天生的l1类型的规范
is natural sort of l1 type of norm for
矩阵
matrices
这是你拥有了l1范西格玛
it's the l1 norm you have that Sigma
矢量这将是l2的规范
vector this would be the l2 norm of the
西格玛因子即L
Sigma factor that would be the L
无穷大规范注意到矢量
infinity norm notice that the vector
数字无穷大为1会发生变化
numbers infinity to 1 gets changed
当你看矩阵时，大约2
around 2 when you look at the matrix
那么这是一个令人兴奋的想法吧
well so that's an exciting idea and it
还有待证明的是人
remains to be proved people are
尝试看看它说的是它
experimenting to see does it say is it
真正
true
是的，所以这是一个未来是的好吧
yep so that's a future yes okay so
那是今天我们谈论的规范
that's today we've talked about norms
这部分笔记将是
and this section of the notes will be
关于规范我们已经迈出了一大步
all about norms we've taken a big leap
在评论深度学习和
in to comment about deep learning and
这是我想说的话最多，
this is what I want to say the most and
我说给每个班级我的教
I say it to every class I teach at the
我学期开始了
near the start of the semester my
感觉我的工作就是教
feeling about what my job is is to teach
你的事情或加入你加入你
you things or to join you join with you
学习今天发生的事情
in learning things as has happened today
这不是你的评分，我不花任何钱
it's not to grade you I don't spend any
时间就像失去睡眠你们都应该
time like like losing sleep y'all should
那个人应该拿一点还是一点
should that person take up one point or
把它变成epsilon惩罚
epsilon penalty for for turning it in
几分钟迟到
for minutes late
你好，我们有很多东西
hello with that right we've got a lot to
做到这一点，无论如何我们会继续
do here and so anyway we'll get on with
一份工作，所以家庭作业三上来，我们
a job so homework three coming up and we
使用你已经拥有的笔记
be using the notes that you already have
为那些人发布了四星
posted in stellar four for those
部分八九等，并
sections eight and nine and so on and
星期一我们会继续，好的，看到你
we'll keep going on Monday okay see you
周一，周末愉快
Monday and have a great weekend
您
you